Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Peter A. Schweitzer Papers, 1916-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Peter A. Schweitzer papers 1916-2005 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company.
18.0 linear feet Extent: 12,000 Items
Established in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Peter A. Schweitzer was an executive with JWT in the New York and Detroit offices, serving as Chief Executive Officer of the agency 2001-2004. Collection spans the years 1916-2005 with the bulk of materials spanning 1980-2000 and includes texts for speeches and presentations, correspondence and other administrative records, printed materials, photographs and slides, and audiovisual materials (audio and video cassettes, CDs and DVDs) that primarily document Schweitzer's career as an executive, especially with JWT's Detroit Office. Companies represented in the collection include Brouillard Communications, Burger King, Ford, Kodak, Kraft, Nestlé, Rolex, and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.10079
Language: Material in English Spanish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Unpublished materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from the date of creation.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Peter A. Schweitzer Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006-2007.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1961 BA, University of Michigan
1961-1967 General Foods, manufacturing and marketing management
1969 Senior Account Executive, Grey Advertising
1971 Vice President, Grey Advertising
1973 Vice President, Kenyon & Eckhardt
1975 Management Supervisor, JWT New York Office (Warner-Lambert account)
1976 Vice President, Group Management Supervisor (Burger King account), JWT
1986 Executive Vice President, JWT USA; General Manager, JWT Detroit Office; elected to JWT Board of Directors
1988 Vice Chairman, Agency Operations, JWT
1993 Named President and Chief Operating Officer of JWT; Worldwide Director of Ford account
1994 Relinquish title of Chief Operating Officer, JWT, to concentrate on Ford account
2001 Chief Executive Officer, JWT
2004 Chairman, JWT; Retired from JWT later in year
2005 Chairman Emeritus, JWT
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1916-2005 with the bulk of materials spanning 1980-2000 and includes texts for speeches and presentations, correspondence and other administrative records, printed materials, photographs and slides, and audiovisual materials (audio and video cassettes, CDs and DVDs) that primarily document Schweitzer's career as an executive, especially with JWT's Detroit Office. Companies represented in the collection include Brouillard Communications, Burger King, Ford, Kodak, Kraft, Nestlé, Rolex, and Unilever.
Collection Arrangement
Collection arranged into seven series: Account Files; Administrative Files; New Business Records; Printed Materials; Writings and Speeches; Large-Format Materials; and Audiovisual Materials.
Subject Headings
Schweitzer, Peter A.; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office; Brouillard Communications; Burger King Corporation; Eastman Kodak Company; Ford Motor Company; Kraft Foods Company; Nestlé; Unilever (Firm); Advertising; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; Audiocassettes; CDs; DVDs; Photographs; Videocassettes; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company collections held in the Hartman Center:
Account Files
Domestic Advertisements
International Offices
New Business Records
Detailed Description of Collection
- Account Files, 1977-2005 and undated
  Includes correspondence, policy statements, presentations and other reports. Arranged alphabetically.
  Restrictions on Access: Unpublished materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from the date of creation.
  - Burger King
    - RGM training (Harry Clark), 1979 (Box 1)
    - Strategy, 1977-1980 (Box 1)
  - DeBeers (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 1)
  - Domino's Pizza (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 1)
  - Ford (Box 1)
    - Australia, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - Broyhill Executive Lecture (Harold Poling), 1990 (Box 1)
    - Communications Guidelines for Launching New Products, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Ford/Europe (Eric Salama, Martin Sorrell), 1994 (Box 1)
    - Ford/JWT marketing relationship--Ford 2000, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Ford/Thompson Times, 2004 (Box 1)
      [Includes articles on environmentalism, Mazda in Russia]
    - Global branding, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Global Business Partnership, financial results 1986-1997, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Global Business Unit, 1995 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Letters of terms, 1982-1997, (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Letters of terms, 1982-1997, (3 of 3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Media, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
    - Media consolidation, 1993-1998 (Box 2)
    - Mission, values, principles, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - Motorsports, 1993-1998 (Box 2)
    - Mustang Museum, 1996-1999 (Box 2)
    - New Ford dealers, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
    - One Hundred Club speech (Tom Wagner), 1990 (Box 2)
    - Organization, 1989-1999, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Organization/Press releases, 1998-2005 (Box 3)
    - Outdoor creative, undated (Box 3)
    - Retail network, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Retail network/Automotive retail marketing, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Rough Riders, Ford Motorsports, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Southeast Asia, 1990-1995 (Box 3)
    - Worldwide marketing best practices meeting, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Hertz (Box 3)
    - Success Transfer: Building Global Synergies, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Kodak (Box 3)
    - Kodak Worldwide, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Performance for Growth (Colby Chandler), 1985 (Box 3)
  - Kraft (Box 3)
    - Nabisco printed materials (Ritz, Ritz Bits, Cheese Nips), undated (Box 3)
    - Oscar Mayer booklet, undated (Box 3)
  - Lipton (Box 3)
    - Budget loss and correspondence, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Nestlé (Box 3)
    - Intern orientation, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Magnum in Europe, undated (Box 3)
    - Smarties presentation, undated (Box 3)
    - What Makes the Difference in Bulk Ice Cream?, undated (Box 4)
  - Rolex (Box 4)
    - 11th Rolex Awards book, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Booklet, Every Rolex Tells a Story, undated (Box 4)
  - R.T. French (Box 4)
    - New product development, 1983 (Box 4)
  - S.C. Johnson (Box 4)
    - Ten Tried and Trusted Methods of Getting the Least from Your Advertising Agency (W. Lee Preschel), 1983 (Box 4)
  - Sprint (Box 4)
    - World Marketing Conference, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Timex (Box 4)
    - Positioning discussion, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Unilever (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan (Box 4)
    - Volunteer notebook, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Warner-Lambert (Box 4)
    - Defending the Brand Management System (Steve Wilgar), 1984 (Box 4)
  - Restricted Materials (Box 4)
    - Adams (Box 4)
      - Cadbury materials and general correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
    - DeBeers (Box 5)
      - Budget review and general correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
    - Diageo (Box 5)
      - Global business review and general correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
    - Diamond Trading Company (Box 5)
      - Presentations, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Domino's Pizza (Box 5)
      - Presentations and general correspondence (Box 5)
    - Ford (Box 5)
      - Beijing Auto Show, 2004 (Box 5)
      - Centennial, 2003 (Box 5)
      - China, 2004 (Box 5)
      - Gobal Business Partnership, 2001 (Box 5)
      - Global Business Unit Conference, 2003, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Global planning, 2003 (Box 5)
      - Media, 2000-2002 (Box 5)
      - Product Day, 2000 (Box 5)
      - VOC process, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Kellogg (Box 5)
      - Presentations and general correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 5)
    - Kimberly-Clark (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
    - K-Mart (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 5)
    - KPMG (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Kraft (Box 5)
      - Management Update, 2002 (Box 5)
      - Nabisco strategy, 2002 (Box 5)
      - Presentations, 2000-2004 (Box 5)
    - Merrill Lynch (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
    - Miller Brewing (Box 6)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Nestlé (Box 6)
      - Battle of the Bulge (Manila presentation), 2002 (Box 6)
      - Ice cream communications review (Melbourne), 2003 (Box 6)
      - Kit-Kat campaign, 2002 (Box 6)
    - Pepsi (Box 6)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Pfizer (Box 6)
      - Presentations and general correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
    - Qwest (Box 6)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Reckitt Benckiser (Box 6)
      - Presentation, 2003 (Box 6)
    - Roche (Box 6)
      - Presentations and general correspondence, 2003 (Box 6)
    - Siemens (Box 6)
      - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Unilever (Box 6)
      - Health and personal care review, 2000 (Box 6)
      - Presentations and general correspondence, 2000-2004, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Vodafone (Box 7)
      - Global Business Review, 2002 (Box 7)
    - Warner-Lambert (Box 7)
      - Performance review, 2001 (Box 7)
    - White Castle (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 7)
- Administrative Files, 1916-2005 and undated (Box 7)
  - Advertising genius competition, undated (Box 8)
  - Brouillard Communications (Box 8)
    - Business to Business Opportunity for JWT, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 8)
  - Compensation philosophy, undated (Box 8)
  - Congratulatory notes, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Copy effectiveness, 1990 and undated (Box 8)
  - DEA communications brief, undated (Box 8)
  - Eyes on Thompson, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Intuition Group, 1998-1999 (Box 8)
  - Invitation--Presidential inauguration, 2005 (Box 8)
  - Invitation--Sporting Clays shoot (Rick Finley Memorial Foundation), 1997 (Box 8)
  - JWT.com, undated (Box 8)
  - JWT fact file, 1959-1988 (Box 8)
  - JWT Group, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Media, 1995-1997 (Box 8)
  - Media buying, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Michael Cooper-Evans, 1988-1990 (Box 8)
  - Miles Colebrook, 1989-1990 (Box 8)
  - Mission statements, 1994-1997 (Box 8)
  - New business correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Offices (Box 9)
    - Asia/Pacific, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Atlanta, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Australia, 1993-1999 (Box 9)
    - Brazil, 1990-1998 (Box 9)
    - China, 1989-1996 (Box 9)
    - Europe, 1990-1995, (2 folders) (Box 9)
    - Europe--Keep Plan, 1988 (Box 9)
    - European succession, 1989 (Box 9)
    - France, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Germany, 1987-1991 (Box 9)
    - India (New office opening, mainly photographs), 2002-2004, (3 folders) (Box 9)
    - Istanbul, 1997-1999, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Japan, 1992-1998 (Box 10)
    - JWT West booklet, undated (Box 10)
    - Korea, 1988-1990 (Box 10)
    - Latin America, 1987-1998 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Los Angeles, 1988-1997 (Box 10)
    - Madrid (New office opening, mainly photographs), 2002 (Box 10)
    - Mexico, 1988-1997 (Box 10)
    - New Zealand, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Philadelphia, undated (Box 11)
    - Russia, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - South Africa, 1989-1997 (Box 11)
    - Taiwan, 1988-1995 (Box 11)
    - Vancouver, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Venezuela, invitation to ceremony for Bobby Coimbra, 2003 (Box 11)
  - Press releases, 1994-2002, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Rome Senior Partners' Conference, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Statement of policies, 1979-1999, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Strategic plan, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Thompson Standard, undated (Box 11)
  - Training/development (John Furr), 1990-1999 (Box 12)
  - Website design, 1995 (Box 12)
  - WPP (Box 12)
    - JWT acquisition, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Martin Sorrell, 1987-1997 (Box 12)
    - Martin Sorrell meeting, 1993 (Box 12)
    - WPP Subsidiaries, 1998-2000 (Box 12)
  - Write if You Want Work advertisement, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Restricted Materials (Box 12)
    - Branding, 2005 and undated (Box 13)
    - Business continuity plan, 2003 (Box 13)
    - CEO announcements, 2001-2003 (Box 13)
    - Chief Executive reading file, 1916-2003, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - European Managers' Meeting, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Growth Group, 2005 (Box 13)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1992-2003 (Box 13)
    - John Holmes, 2002 (Box 13)
    - Joint Venture with Wunderman, 2003 (Box 13)
    - Mindshare, 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - North American Managers' Meeting, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Office of Chief Executive, 2001-2003 (Box 14)
    - Offices (Box 14)
      - Atlanta, 2002 (Box 14)
      - Australia, 2000-2001 (Box 14)
      - Brazil, 2000-2002 (Box 14)
      - Chicago, 2003 (Box 14)
      - Geneva, 2002 (Box 14)
      - Houston, 2002-2003 (Box 14)
      - Japan, 2004 (Box 14)
      - London, 2000-2004, (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Mexico, 2001 (Box 14)
      - Singapore, 2001 (Box 14)
      - Taiwan, 2001 (Box 14)
      - Tokyo/Shanghai, 2003 (Box 14)
    - Partner nominations, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Project Phoenix, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Reader file, 2001, (1-2 of 4 folders) (Box 14)
    - Reader file, 2001, (3-4 of 4 folders) (Box 15)
    - Reader file, 2002, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Reader file, 2003, (1 of 3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Reader file, 2003, (2-3 of 3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Reader file, 2004, (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Thompson Total Branding, 2001 (Box 16)
    - Training/development (John Furr), 2001-2002 (Box 16)
    - University of Michigan Presidential Societies, 2002 (Box 16)
    - Visit to Duke University, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Wall Street Journal, 2003 (Box 16)
    - WPP (Box 16)
      - Acquisitions, 2000-2002 (Box 16)
      - Industry Review Meeting, 2001 (Box 16)
      - Martin Sorrell, 2002-2003 (Box 16)
      - Meeting notes, 1999-2001 (Box 16)
- New Business Records, 2001-2003 [RESTRICTED] (Box 16)
  - AARP, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Burger King, 2001 (Box 17)
  - Ford of Canada, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Home Depot, 2001-2002 (Box 17)
  - K-Mart, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Michelin, 2001 (Box 17)
  - New Balance, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Philip Morris, 2001 (Box 17)
  - Shell, 2001-2003 (Box 17)
- Printed Materials and Memorabilia, 1979-2005 and undated (Box 17)
  - Strategic Review 2002-2004, 2001 [Restricted] (Box 17)
  - 125th anniversary license plate and pin, circa 1989 (Box 18)
  - A Short History of the JWT Detroit Office, 2001 (Box 18)
  - Adcrafter Roster Edition, 2005 (Box 18)
  - Board meeting materials, 1993 (Box 18)
  - Brand Management: A Guide to a Few Misconceptions, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Buying…It's Not an Event, It's a System, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Colorado brochures, undated (Box 18)
  - Creative Selling credentials, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Endless Brand Experience, 2001 (Box 18)
  - Executive Focus clippings, 2004 (Box 18)
  - In-Signs Qualitative Research, State of the Family in America, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Integrated Marketing Communications--A Return to Basics, 2000 (Box 18)
  - JWT Specialized Communications, 2000 (Box 18)
  - People Buy Brands, Not Products, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Psychology Today, Dictionary of Advertising Terms, 1979 (Box 18)
  - San Francisco brochures, undated (Box 18)
  - Tate Modern, 2004 (Box 18)
  - The Goose that Laid the Golden Egg (Aesop), undated (Box 18)
  - Thompson Total Targeting, undated (Box 19)
  - United Markets of Europe, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Wall Street Journal, feature on media, 2005 (Box 19)
  - Writing Plans and Recommendations (AAAA), 1977 (Box 19)
- Writings and Speeches (Chronological File), 1978-2005 and undated (Box 19)
  - Undated (Box 20)
    - 1 on 1 speech (Box 20)
    - Brand/Client Consultancy (Box 20)
    - Brand Management from the Other End of the Telescope (Box 20)
    - Brands Are People Too (Box 20)
    - Car Neglect (Box 20)
    - Creative Quality Audit (Box 20)
    - Global Future of Advertising (Burt Manning) (Box 20)
    - How Do You Develop An Effective Auto Ad Campaign (Box 20)
    - IBM Marketing and Brand Management (Box 20)
    - It's a Small World (Box 20)
    - Leadership in Total Brand Communications (Box 20)
    - Lead, Follow, Or… (Box 20)
    - Management Organization (Box 20)
    - Managers' Meeting--Charles Balestrino roast (Ron Burns) (Box 20)
    - Managing the Client/Agency Relationship (Box 20)
    - MS Society presentation (Box 20)
    - North American Managers' Meeting (Box 20)
    - Palm Beach talk (Box 20)
    - Presentation to Roy Glah (Ron Burns) (Box 20)
    - Public Relations: What It Isn't and Is (Wallace Clayton) (Box 20)
    - Review of JWT Brand Positioning (Box 20)
    - Society Bank Michigan Lunch and Learn series (Box 20)
    - Strategic Plan (Box 20)
    - Thompson Connect presentation (Box 20)
    - Welcome for new staff members (Steve Brown) (Box 20)
    - What's Good for the World Is Good for General Motors (Sean Fitzpatrick) (Box 20)
    - Winners/Losers commentary (Box 20)
    - Worldwide Board Meeting (Box 20)
    - You Can Bet on It (Box 20)
  - 1978 (Box 20)
    - Everything Changes but the People (Burt Manning) (Box 20)
  - 1981 (Box 20)
    - If Advertising Were Our Client, What Would We Tell Him? (Don Johnston) (Box 20)
  - 1982 (Box 20)
    - Happy Guy Fawkes Day (David Campbell-Harris) (Box 20)
    - How to Succeed in and Prepare for the Effective Management of People within a Business Environment (Don Robertson) (Box 20)
    - T-Plan (Box 20)
  - 1983 (Box 20)
    - Advertising Execution in the 80s (Bernard Owett) (Box 21)
    - Women and Advertising (Rena Bartos) (Box 21)
  - 1984 (Box 21)
    - Discus Conference (Box 21)
    - National vs. Local Media (Box 21)
  - 1985 (Box 21)
    - Roots of Communication (Burt Manning) (Box 21)
  - 1986 (Box 21)
    - Detroit Office meeting (Box 21)
    - FDAF Chairman's meeting (Box 21)
    - Motor City Publishers (Box 21)
    - Welcome to Detroit (Box 21)
  - 1987 (Box 21)
    - Advertising in the Pressure Cooker (Jack Cronin) (Box 21)
    - In Our Hands (Burt Manning) (Box 21)
    - Staff meeting (Box 21)
    - FDAF Chairman's meeting (Box 21)
    - Field Force meeting (Box 21)
    - Review of European Advertising (Joseph Schulte) (Box 21)
  - 1988 (Box 21)
    - Adcraft lunch (Burt Manning) (Box 21)
    - Eyes on Thompson (Box 21)
    - J. Walter Thompson--A Legend in His Own Time (Marion Howington) (Box 21)
  - 1989 (Box 21)
    - Advertising in the 21st Century (Burt Manning) (Box 21)
    - All Staff meeting (Charles Balestrino) (Box 21)
    - Asia/Pacific tour--J. Walter…Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow (Box 21)
    - Asia/Pacific visitation (Box 21)
    - Don Robertson retirement speeches (Roy Glah, Wayne Fickinger) (Box 21)
    - FASPAC Marketing Forum (Box 21)
    - Historical presentation (Box 21)
    - J. Walter…Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow (Box 21)
    - Media--The New Creative Frontier (Burt Manning) (Box 21)
    - Newark District FDAA (Box 22)
    - Service recognition awards (Box 22)
  - 1989-1994 (Box 22)
    - Anniversary talks (Box 22)
  - 1990 (Box 22)
    - Advertising Research Foundation (Box 22)
    - ARF Copy Workshop (Box 22)
    - JWT Long-Range Plan 1991-1996 (Don Sullivan) (Box 22)
    - Los Angeles Auto Show (R.L. Rewey) (Box 22)
    - Newark District FDAA (Box 22)
  - 1990-1997 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous speech materials (Box 22)
  - 1991 (Box 22)
    - Ford Regional Managers Meeting (Box 22)
    - J.D. Power and Associates Roundtable (Box 22)
    - Video presentation script (Box 22)
    - WPP Board meeting (Roy Glah) (Box 22)
  - 1992 (Box 22)
    - Adcraft Club (Allen Thomas) (Box 22)
    - Beyond Operations (Ron Burns) (Box 22)
    - China: The Fragmenting Consumer Market (Ron Cromie) (Box 22)
    - Enter the Dragon (China; Grace Atkinson) (Box 22)
    - Europe in Focus (Allen Thomas, Miles Colebrook) (Box 22)
    - FDAF meeting (Box 22)
    - Highway to Excellence (Sean Fitzpatrick) (Box 22)
    - Japan presentation: 1991 Review, 1992 Outlook (Box 22)
    - J.D. Power and Associates (Box 23)
    - JWT Europe presentation (Box 23)
    - Media Research (Robert Mancini) (Box 23)
    - Shocking Truth About Advertising from the Secret Files of Madison Avenue (Sean Fitzpatrick) (Box 23)
    - The Pendulum Must Swing Back (Robert James) (Box 23)
    - War and Soap (Sean Fitzpatrick) (Box 23)
    - Washington Automotive Press Association (Box 23)
  - 1993 (Box 23)
    - Adcrafter Club of Detroit (Box 23)
    - Brand speech (Box 23)
    - Financial Analysts meeting (Box 23)
    - Ford 50th anniversary (Box 23)
    - Integrated Communications Workshop: The Old Grey Mare… (Box 23)
    - It's a Small World (Box 23)
    - JWT Long-Term Plan (Box 23)
    - Philadelphia FDAF (Box 23)
    - Speech to London Office (Burt Manning) (Box 23)
    - State of the Agency Business (Martin Sorrell) (Box 23)
    - Washington Automotive Group, Fat Lady Sings (Box 23)
    - Worldwide Board Meeting (Box 23)
    - Worldwide Board of Directors, Integrated Marketing (Box 23)
  - 1994 (Box 23)
    - Advertising's Future: TV or Not TV? (Burt Manning) (Box 23)
    - All Staff meeting (not delivered) (Box 23)
    - Creative Research in the 1990s (Box 23)
    - Detroit all-staff meeting (Box 23)
    - European Managers Meeting (Box 23)
    - Financial Analysts meeting (Box 23)
    - Food and Drink presentation (Miles Colbrook) (Box 24)
    - How JWT Sees Itself (Box 24)
    - How to Add Value to the Brand (interview with João Proença) (Box 24)
    - It's a Small World (Box 24)
    - JWT North American Board Meeting (Box 24)
    - New Life in the City--The Greening of Detroit (Box 24)
    - North American Board Meeting (Box 24)
    - Odyssey of the Commodore (Bill Thompson) (Box 24)
    - Radio Forum (Robert Mancini) (Box 24)
    - Rome Conference (Box 24)
    - Steve Brown reception (Box 24)
    - Strategic Plan (Chris Jones) (Box 24)
    - Things I've Learned About Global Marketing While Wearing Out Two Passports (Box 24)
  - 1995 (Box 24)
    - Adcraft Career Symposium (Box 24)
    - Brand speech (Kinder Essington) (Box 24)
    - Comments on Montreux Detroit Jazz Festival poster (Box 24)
    - Creating Maximum Bandwidth (Burt Manning) (Box 24)
    - Creative Dissatisfaction (Burt Manning) (Box 24)
    - Detroit Office Christmas party (Box 24)
    - Economic Club of Detroit, introduction of Larry King (Box 24)
    - Financial Analysts meeting (Box 24)
    - Fiuggi World Partners (Box 24)
    - Ford Hispanic talk (Box 24)
    - Innovation (Jim Patterson) (Box 24)
    - Midas--Road to the Future (Box 24)
    - Museum of Advertising--Driving the American Dream (Box 24)
    - Putting Your Brand on Sponsorships (Burt Manning) (Box 24)
    - Re-Engineering the Advertising Agency (Autoweek meeting) (Box 24)
    - Rome speech (Box 24)
    - Strategic plan (William Eccleshare) (Box 25)
    - Technology Consultancy (Don Topping) (Box 25)
    - The Strategic Plan--Making It Happen (Box 25)
  - 1996 (Box 25)
    - All Staff Meeting (Box 25)
    - Brand speech (Steve Brown) (Box 25)
    - Brand speech, Western Michigan University (Box 25)
    - Crain Communications annual meeting (Box 25)